SEAN C. LEHMAN (812) 212-2543

FISHERS, IN 46037

E-mail: lehmansean@hotmail.com

Seeking a position as a Full Stack Junior Developer in the Microsoft .NET Framework using C#

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Graduate of ElevenFifty Academy in the Microsoft .NET Framework Track

- Using Visual Studio to create ASP .NET software applications
- Using Azure to deploy applications
- Agile 16 hours of instruction
- C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Confluence, Git, Jira
- Seminars in Security, Testing, UX/UI Design, Debugging, Front End Design, Web Deployment

Engineering professional with competencies in designing, conceptualizing and managing projects that will increase productivity and overall profit margins. Fifteen years of successful experience in material handling project management, integrated systems design, productivity improvement, inside and outside sales, customer service, order processing, plant operations analysis and computer skills involving AutoCAD, Microsoft Word, Excel and Outlook.

EXPERIENCE

LEHMAN CLOCK REPAIR, Batesville, IN/Fishers, IN 2008 - Present

General Manager/Customer Service: Repair of grandfather, antique mantel, wall and cuckoo clocks, Registered Service Center for Howard Miller and Ridgeway clocks.

- Troubleshooting to determine most effective repair or replacement
- Testing of repair performance to reduce warranty claims and increase quality control, customer satisfaction and company brand
- Generated customer job ticket program to track repair progress, movement details, time studies troubleshooting and customer communication and follow up
- Developed scheduling system for future preventive maintenance and increasing customer base to generate future sales pipeline
- Customer education of their product, its operation and pitfalls
- Fabrication of jigs and test stands for testing of movement operation
- Managed invoicing, accounts receivable, installation, relocation and warranty claims

INTERSYSTEMS, Omaha, NE Inside Sales Engineer/Design Engineer 2005 - 2008 2006-2008 - Inside Sales Engineer for entire product line:

- Provided detailed, engineered quotes to contractors for Bucket Elevators, Drag Chain Conveyors, Enclosed Belt Conveyors, Samplers, Bulkweighers, and Truck Probes.
- Streamlined quoting procedure to eliminate manual logging, paper printout and filing.

- 2005-2006 Design Engineer for Bucket Elevator product line:
- Produced AutoCAD shop drawings from customer orders, verifying engineering information (drive shaft sizing, motor and reducer selection, belt and cup selection, explosion vent sizing, belt speed, bearing selection and other specs) using Excel spreadsheet calculation programs.
- Designed special infeed hoppers, leg sections, head, boot and boot cover sections.

PRATER INDUSTRIES, INC., Bolingbrook, IL Application Sales Engineer 2002 - 2004

- Customer service including equipment option recommendations for the application, quoting, purchasing, ordering, RMA and troubleshooting.
- Updated and streamlined quotation procedure, Revised quote request form.

KRAUTER STORAGE SYSTEMS, INC., Indianapolis, IN Sales/Design Engineer 1997-2002

- Prepared project costs and proposals for capital expenditure requests, provided solutions with a calculated ROI and increased productivity. Examples below:
- ALCOA CSI Designed and managed installation of a turnkey 40' x 40' 2-story in-plant office building including HVAC system, sprinkler system, flooring, lighting and electrical system. \$80,000 project.
- Great Dane Trailers Analyzed customer's method for storage of parts at the assembly line, changed the process to become more organized while increasing efficiency, improving inventory control and restocking time. \$25,000 project
- Thomson Consumer Electronics Generic order picking system that handled 90% of the
 customer's package sizes, allowing the layout to be dictated by part number instead of
 carton size. Increased efficiency and accuracy of picks as well as restocking and
 inventory control. \$65,000 project

PROGRESSIVE HANDLING, INC., Elkhart, IN Sales/Design Engineer 1994-1997

- Project management and design of integrated conveyor systems involving specially designed and built equipment, electrical controls and mechanical installations. Project Examples:
- McCormick & Company Engineered a conveying system for a process that would change in 2 years. Designed the central piece of equipment to accommodate future upgrades with minimal expense and effort. \$150,000 project
- Central Soya Designed an integrated conveyor system to automate finished product packaging. Resulted in re-tasking of personnel and increased efficiency of the operation as well as improving quality control. \$250,000 project

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

ElevenFifty Academy, Carmel, IN, Microsoft .NET Accelerated Learning Program

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, BS Degree, Computer Integrated Manufacturing

Howard Miller, Repair Certification